perfetto, so we are good to go
ok
ok, so
what is
Fabrizio, sorry
yeah, just so
dico il volo in italiano
che stai registrando con OBS Studio
e non so se sei già utilizzato
ho visto che non hai però messo l'audio
in ingresso
quindi non penso che tu stai registrando la voce
in realtà perché hai messo tanto cattura schermo
devi fare un plus
ma in realtà vedo che
lo sto registrando
perché vedo la barra che scorre
eh, quello sì, ok
la barra scorre, però se non la metti in fonti
non te lo registra
lo registra tutto quanto quello che vede in fonti
lo schermo lo sta catturando
l'audio là te lo mette in automatico
che sente qualcosa
però ovviamente e cattura audio
penso per ti però audio è entrata
cattura di un'entrata
e del tuo microfono
spesso perché io lo scelgo
non lo scelgo
sì sì, va bene, non lo scelgo
grazie, grazie
perché poi magari registravi
e poi non si vede in attesa
perché mi è già capitata a me anche
ah, benissimo
ok
così dovrebbe andare
ok, perfetto
devo riavviare la registrazione oppure cattura comunque anche partendo da qui
no, no, no, cattura da adesso
da quando l'ho imposto
ok, perfetto
ok, grazie mille
ok
so
vehicle function
is
is basically
a functional
specification
for
as you can
as you can understand
from
from the name
regarding
a
vehicle
functionality
a
functional
specification
is
functional
specification
just
is
is a document
that
includes
all the
all the tasks
that a given
functionality
has to
has to carry out
including
contents
both functional
and some
and something
also regarding
the diagnostic
of a given
functionality
but
as you may
already know
some of you
at least
the
the diagnostic
is not
the master
document of the
diagnostic
is not
the vehicle
function itself
but is the
is the
CDP
ok
so
a functional
specification
is
a
as I already
said
is a document
and
VF
is
must include
everything
that regards
the history
of the
functionality
so
any changes
that
that are made
to the
functionality
during
during its
existence
from the
beginning
to the
end
have to be
traced
into this
document
so
we'll see an
example
in the
following
but just
keep in
mind
that
that the
changes
are always
kept
track
are always
kept
track
of
so
at least
the
changes
that
are made
across
from
one
version
to
another
so
in the
document
you will
see
yeah
but
anyway
you will
see
an
example
in
the
following
so
let's
just
give
a
theoretical
overview
and
we
will
see
a
practical
example
in
the
following
as I
said
the
vehicle
function
is
related
to
functionality
and
not
to
the
component
structure
so
it's
something
that
is
on
a
different
level
of
abstraction
to
the
hardware
component
or
components
because
a
vehicle
functionality
is
not
deployed
is
not
embedded
into
a
single
may
not
be
included
into
a
single
hardware
component
but
a
vehicle
functionality
could
involve
different
issues
sensors
actuators
and so
on
so
the
vehicle
function
is
on
a
different
level
of
abstraction
than
the
physical
layer
the
VF
is
the
starting
point
that
is
used
by
the
developers
to
write
the
software
to
code
software
so
it
shall
be
it
should
be
quite
clear
and
quite
comprehensive
of
what
the
functionality
has
to
do
so
let's
go
ahead
this is
where
the
vehicle
function
is on
the
left
side
of
the
cycle
is
at
this
level
of
the
cycle
so
it's
a
requirement
of
it's
a
high
level
requirement
higher
than
the
software
requirements
for
example
and
let's
go
ahead
what
are
the
functionalities
for
which
we
can
find
a
corresponding
VF
as a
document
car access
theft
protection
regarding
vehicle
level
functionalities
vehicle
dynamics
braking
systems
also
things
regarding
vehicle
access
wiping
everything
that
anything
that is
a
functionality
of
any
vehicle
level
I mean
it could
be a
vehicle
level
functionality
a
power
train
functionality
or
ADAS
functionality
anything
that is
any
functionality
that is
presented
in the
vehicle
is
formalized
into
a
document
like
the one
that we
will see
the following
so
this is
the naming
convention
function
name
the name
the number
of the
function
and
the number
of the
function
and the
release
the version
and the
release
of the
function
yeah
here
there's
an
example
I'm
an
attino
management
this is
the
number
this is
the
version
number
and the
release
number
so as I
said
the
vehicle
function
is something
that is
not
strictly
related
to the
physical
component
and to
the
vehicle
and to
the
platform
to the
vehicle
architecture
so in
the
document
you may
find
something
that
some
notes
at the
beginning
of the
vehicle
function
that report
what are the
changes
that are
made
to that
specific
version
of the
vehicle
function
to
adapt
to a
given
architecture
for
example
if a
new
platform
is being
developed
but I
want to
port
that
functionality
from
an
old
architecture
to
another
I
may
decide
to
use
the
same
requirement
the
same
vehicle
function
with
some
changes
I
can
decide
to
carry
over
that
functionality
from
the
old
architecture
beginning
of
the
document
you
may
find
some
notes
regarding
the
changes
that
have
been
made
to
that
version
of
the
functionality
most
important
part
of
the
vehicle
function
in
my
opinion
at
least
for
those
of
you
that
will
actually
it's
important
for
everyone
because
it
gives
a
graphical
form
to
the
interactions
of
the
different
parts
of
the
different
systems
that
are
involved
in
the
functionality
is
the
functional
diagram
the
functional
diagram
here
you
probably
cannot
see
it
very
clearly
but
if
you
give me
a second
I
can
download
the
example
so that
you can
see it
in
practice
can
oh
Oh, something that I didn't, I mentioned at the beginning of the lesson that all the changes have to be, have to be traced into the, into the document.
Inside the revision notes, you may find also this table like this. In this table are reported, are reported also change, the CRs, that is the change requests.
This table, this table is, is a very short history of the changes that have been made, at least for, for, for bullet points.
The main changes that have been made to the, that have been made to the vehicle function along its life.
For example, here, you can see that the list of all the CRs, with all the paragraphs and the, all the paragraphs that have been modified in the parameters that, that, that are going to, that are, that have been added or deleted.
Now, let's go to the important part, the functional diagram.
Oops.
As I already mentioned, the most important part is the functional diagram.
Unfortunately, I don't have the original version of this document, because here the, during the, the, the PDF printing process, the, the functional diagram has been cut.
But, uh, this is the functional diagram. The functional diagram, uh, formalizes all the interactions in terms of messages and signals that are exchanged, uh, between the different issues, uh, and the signals reported are the ones that are used by the, uh, by the given functionality.
Here, you see that in the squares, the, the, the square, the, the, the square blocks, it's the issues, these ones are the signals that are used, that are given as input to the, to different issues, uh, coming, uh, that, uh, that, uh, that are outputs of other functionalities, basically, that are also reporting the functional diagrams.
And, uh, this one is a physical button.
Um, and, uh, this one is something that is displayed on the PC.
This one could be, uh, could be lights, uh, messages that appear on the, uh, that appear in the dashboard, uh, butters and so on any physical or, uh, audio signal that is, uh, that is, um, that is a physical interface to the user.
So, uh, the functional diagram gives, uh, a complete overview of, uh, all the interactions between the different components that are involved in a given functionality, the components and the, uh, signals and the, uh, respective messages that contain the signals.
Another thing that I mentioned at the beginning of the presentation was that, uh, um, in the document, uh, there is, uh, um, along with the, with the notes that we, uh, that we just saw, uh, there will be some track of the changes that are made across the different versions of the vehicle function.
Uh, uh, uh, what do I mean with this statement?
I mean that, uh, when a change is made by, uh, by a CR, for example, going from one release to another, the things that, that are, uh, that have been changed respect to the old release are still present in the document.
So that I can see the parts that have been modified or deleted, I can still see them in the document, for example, here, you can see the T red as a revision, there's the part that, uh, there's the part that have been modified and the parts that have been related that have been deleted are still present, but they are barred.
So that, uh, uh, uh, this is a great help for both the developers that have to, uh, that have to change the software that have to change the software implementation, um, uh, and also for the, uh, for, for the ones that carry out the validation.
Because, uh, uh, a change request involves, uh, a change in the software and also change in the test cases that you may, uh, that you may have already written, uh, to that point.
So this is very useful because, uh, uh, if you keep track of the things that have been changed, you can, uh, you can just, you can directly go to the, uh, to the test list that you've already made and make the modifications to, uh, to the past, to the test cases that have been affected without touching the old ones.
You can delete, uh, you can, uh, you can, uh, modify, you can, uh, by modifying the test cases, I mean that you delete the old ones and you write new test cases that adapt to the new release so that, uh, when you write a test list, you can, uh, you can keep trace of the, uh, of the changes that have been made so that you can, uh, that you can keep track of the applicability of a given requirement at a given time.
So everything clear regarding the functional, uh, the functional diagram.
Yeah.
Okay.
Guys, let's keep this interactive.
So if you, at any time, if you have any questions, that's, uh, just, uh, just give a shout and let's stop so that we can clarify the doubts, uh, as they, uh, as they come in.
Okay.
Okay, thank you.
So let's go ahead.
Hmm.
Okay.
This part doesn't apply to this requirement.
This is something that is, uh, this something that, uh, that relates to, uh, uh, uh, to a specific OEM this format, the format of the video of the VF is pretty much the same across different, uh, different suppliers,
and the OEMs, uh, if there's one or, uh, or, uh, or, uh, but the structure of the, the structure and the contents of a VF are pretty much the same across different, uh, different suppliers.
And the OEMs, so, yes, can I ask you a question about the, the functional diagram?
So you said, as we see that if there are some changes in the, in the, there's a vital function, there are some changes that are deleted from the previous one, like, would you see something similar in the functional diagram as well?
Like, uh, like, uh, yeah, or you just see, like, what's, what's the new vehicle function doing so you can, uh, yeah, actually this one is, uh, yeah, I'll just answer your question.
Yeah, uh, actually I, I wasn't very, I wasn't very precise on that regarding the functional diagram, since some changes have been made to the vehicle function here in the document, you find two functional diagrams.
You find the old one and the new one, uh, the, uh, basically the, uh, so that you can compare the two.
So you find the, uh, the, the functional diagram in case the change is affected, the functional diagram, uh, you will find the old diagram in, uh, part deleted.
And then one that is, uh, that has been added.
So in case the functional diagram is changed, you, uh, you would find, uh, both the old one and the new one so that you can compare the two.
ok ok thank you ok thank you for your question
ok so let's go on with the presentation and in case we need any help we can use the example
this is something that relates to the everything that relates to a specific supplier i'm just
going to skip it from the presentation i just want to give a complete overview so that you
can have the so that you can have an overview you can have just the common elements across
the different the different oems without without specifying on a on a particular one ok this
one is the operating conditions the working conditions table this part of the document
this table is in my opinion is very important but unfortunately sometimes it is not very
this is not very carefully addressed because some some some people that that are that that
right that right vehicle functions don't find this very useful so they don't address this
in a in a very accurate way what does this table indicate this table indicates indicates
what are the conditions for which are specific on the the vehicle conditions for which a specific
content that corresponds to a specific paragraph in the in the vehicle function is applicable
for example there may be in a specific functionality there may be some contents that are applicable
some requirements that are applicable when the vehicle is in kiosk but are not applicable when
the vehicle in uh in kion and vice versa some parts of the requirement that are applicable when
the when the engine is running while it shall not be uh shall not be addressed it shall not be active
when the uh when the vehicle is in kiosk for example or uh uh some contents some requirements that have to
be excluded when the vehicle is cranking because why do uh for example uh um a valid example of a
situation where a functionality should be included as it should be excluded during crank is the exclusion of
of some diagnosis some diagnosis should be excluded when the vehicle is cranking because um due to the uh to
the voltage drop on the uh on 12 volts bus some uh uh we may have some false diagnosis so some diagnosis
actually almost a great part of the diagnosis should be excluded during the during engine cranking
and uh the same we can tell also for excluded with battery discharge this table has normally more lines
because we may have across different architectures they may have we may have different vehicle
conditions for example this table is valid for a conventional powertrain while this for example an
additional line that you may have with uh that you may find with uh for example with an hybrid architecture
is uh when the vehicle is during uh is uh is uh is operating in a drive mode in a drive mode obviously the uh
the engine is not running because the engine is off but the uh but the vehicle is uh but vehicle is
is operational and is uh is producing traction okay clear
questions regarding the working operation the working conditions table
okay i do have a question what in the key of you on what is the plus 30 and plus 50
like what does it indicate yeah basically it's just the indication of the uh it's just normally the
indication of the uh it's the indication of the uh of the um of the um of the physical key of the physical
key uh of the physical keeping the physical keeping i mean uh um key off means that uh this uh this
varies along uh this varies uh this may vary uh from supplier to from oem to oem normally uh k15 is the
the physical signal of the physical key okay okay so okay 15 uh k15 is on when the physical key is uh
when the physical keys on that's okay okay thank you welcome okay when i said that this part is not
uh it's not very carefully addressed sometimes you can find an example a valid example in the uh
uh in the uh in the attached document for example here this part has not uh has not been uh very
carefully addressed because uh this is basically the list of all the contents that are contained in
this this document and uh and uh basically they're listed in for all operating from for all working
conditions ignition off ignition on time with ignition of uh cut off during starting blah blah blah and all
the all the requirements are all the requirements are listed and uh this is obviously not not true
because uh i can tell you that uh for uh in this case there are some of these requirements that shall
not be uh that shall not be active some contacts that that shall not be active during uh during uh
during some operating conditions
okay but let's go ahead
okay this is just an extract from vf i'll just go through the example that is probably more clear
than the uh than the screenshot of another requirement
okay
so some important information that are not listed in the presentation that can be found in the uh that
can be found in the document uh is for example the list of the of the other vehicle functions that
interact with this one here you can find in the uh in the external interfaces paragraph you can find
the external inputs and the external the external inputs that is the um that is the vehicle functions
the list of the vehicle functions that um that uh that give signals and messages to uh to this
functionality as input like for example here pf026 pf606 pf092 these are all vehicle functionalities that produce
outputs that are given as input to this functionality and they're listed in this part here
same for the vehicle functions uh in this paragraph here you will find all the issues all the uh all the
network nodes that are involved in this functionality bcm that is the body control module uh the slu that is
the shifting level unit epc instrument panel cluster and mta that is managed transmission uh manual transmission
automated that is basically the gearbox issue
another very important part is this one that lists all the um sorry
just going uh backwards to uh be sure that i didn't forget anything another very important part
is this one as you can see uh in the first chapter of the vehicle function there's a lot of useful
information because there's uh there's there's all the all the parts that are involved in terms of
nodes and vehicle functions and as we will see in the following also networks signals and messages
and internal variables that are involved in the function so uh so i'm spending a little bit of time in this
okay so this is the list of the physical input outputs ipc display dot gui this is the assembly of
all the all the um all the physical
all the physical input outputs outputs outputs that are given to and by the user to the uh this is the
way how the external world interacts with the with the vehicle functionality the external world i mean
the driver in fact here in the list you can find the two things that are involved that is the power echo
that is a physical button and the ipc display dot gui that is the assembly of all the signals these are
for example the buzzer uh a telltale on the epc screen um uh something that appears in the in some
display in the pc and so on in the information paragraph there's the list of the hardwired signals
sheet live position dot info that is do you know what uh what dot info is what this uh what this uh suffix here
mean dot info means that in softer terms it's a physics uh it's a it's an internal variable uh normally um
um since it's also reporting in the paragraph this one it's a hardwired signal so it means that it's a
it's an analogic it's a it's a physical signal coming from a from a physical component
for example here shift alert position dot info it's the physical information in terms of combination of
the pins that are connected to the uh to the that are connected to the to the shifting lever that goes
in as an input to the to the functionality i think that this physical input this hardwired signal is
connected to the mta but anyway you can find it in the yeah you can find yeah exactly here's the uh
the shifting level unit shift level the position dot info this is a physical this is a physical signal
that is the translation in term in is the um is the uh transposition of a physical input uh into of a
turn of an outward signal into an internal variable the digital position the teams
okay so the list of the internal variables the proper internal variables you can find them with
the suffix dot info or dot dot rq
and the list of all the signals that uh that are published on the different networks
so hopefully with a short description although this is also the same description that you may find in
the uh in the dbc
so all the signals that are involved in the functionality on the beacon
all the signals that are involved in the functionality are being published on the second
and uh lean that in this case is not applicable since uh no lean components are involved by this
functionality and so on
that's the indication uh the indication paragraph that it's the um it's the list of the things that
you find here in the box
in the in the box uh in this box this shape here with the uh with the dome this rectangle with the
dome is the uh is uh something is something that is um is the uh it's it's the assembly of all the
physical the physical signals that come from the that come from the ipc that come that are um
um as i said the uh the buzzers the uh all the all the internal variables that translate into a
physical input output on the pc a physical output on the ipc either sound or visual
okay this part here this paragraph is the core of the vehicle function because in this file in the
functional requirement paragraph there's the um there's the list of all the contents that have to
be uh that are part of the requirement of the legal functionality basically what the functionality has
to do the tasks the data function ideas to carry out let's say the the uh the the also the algorithm
the the algorithmic part is included if some some calculations have to be carried out or some actions
have to be uh some actions some uh some signals have to be written in a seen a given way as a result
of a combination of a given uh of a given out of the given inputs and so on everything is listed in
this paragraph as i said this is the core of the functionality so let's uh let's give an eye to
the presentation to see if there is something useful that can be added to this part
there is something that relates to diagnosis
actually there's not much information in this presentation so just um i'll directly go through
the document so that you can have a valid uh valid concrete example of what we are talking about
okay
you
here there's the uh there's a list of the uh of the management of all the c of uh there's a
all the every paragraph relates to the management of the signals that are elaborated by uh uh by um
by specific issue
for example
i want to go into something more uh into something more uh more consistent
like this part here for example
okay
oh something that uh something that uh that i didn't mention
the the atomic contents that are listed in this part of the requirement
is the for example bcm management esm management
blinking buzzer warning and fail management
for example this part here this paragraph blinking buzzer warning and fail management is something that
you will find also in the working conditions table
the specific content is that level of paragraph blinking buzzer warning and fail management
is the content that has to be uh that has to be um
uh that is to be active in that specific working condition
okay for example this paragraph here relates this explains how should be managed the uh as you may
understand the blinking buzzer and warning
the uh the algorithms the the functionality that uh that is described in a document uh could be um
could be explained could be uh physically formalized into uh in different ways
a table is one of the ways that uh that could be used in a requirement in a bf to formalize uh
to formalize a requirement
for example here there's a combination of the inputs there's a combination this this
combination of the inputs shall give this output
uh this combination of the uh this combination of the shift level position and the tpbm status that
is the uh the electronic parking brake status uh the combination of these two shall give this output
shall be this output in terms of mismatch condition mismatch condition that translates into something
that the issue no not with you the the functionality must do when the mismatch is detected
in fact this table uh this table explains when the mismatch condition has to be uh has to be uh has
to be detected and in the following you see what happens when the mismatch is detected for example
to to to to to here mta shall send the status c this signal shall be a shall this signal shall be set
to other cases on dawn when a mismatch is detected according to the tables above one and two
okay
gear changing request is another paragraph that is another content that is uh that has to be managed
that can be managed in different uh in different vehicle operating conditions for example this uh
this is a very uh this is a very good example the gear changing request shall not be managed when
the ignition is off because when the ignition is off the vehicle is off everything is off the uh the uh
the epic is off and so on the the vehicle is still with the electronic parking brake deployed and so
on so this functionality shall not be uh shall not be managed when the ignition is off and so this uh
this line here shall not be present in this field it's just to uh to give an example this is the
result of a uh of a reckless copy paste from uh from probably the ignition on part anyway
this is another form of uh of describing an algorithm that you may find in a vehicle function
this is actually a very useful one
uh that is the pseudocode
uh this form is very useful to uh for both the for both the developers and uh
the ones that are uh delegated to write the uh to draft the test cases
because in this way in this way is very uh it's very easy to uh to find all the branches that have
to be covered with the uh with a test list
so as i said this part here regards uh is uh regards the algorithm so
so let's go to some other important information that you may find in a uh that you may find in a
view of function
this is uh this is uh this is still the um the core of the of the functionality okay
as i said you may find in the vehicle function document something that relates to the diagnosis
although this is not the master requirement that is used for uh for diagnosis but um there may be
some overlapping between the functional content and the diagnostic content why is that think about
the recoveries the countermeasures that have to be uh put in place when a fault is detected
uh this is something that is somewhere in between the uh diagnostic content and the functional content
because it relates to diagnosis because it's triggered by the uh by the by the racing of a dtc
but the countermeasure is something that acts on the functional level because it may affect the uh it
may affect the vehicle functionality think about for example the um the the rating of the vehicle
performance that is put in place when a fault is detected like an over temperature for example
transmission over temperature transmission over temperature dtc dtc triggers countermeasure countermeasure
countermeasure is vehicle in limited um in limited limited torque limited power or uh gear locked
or a vehicle locked in neutral
so dtc diagnostic content that triggers something on the physical the on the functional level
so in the vehicle function you may still find something that relates to the vehicle diagnosis
that is when a signal is set um when a signal is set uh to a given value due to a detection of
fault condition a given dtc shall be set
but the reference as you will find in a table like this is still it still refers to this stf
the stf is the uh is the finalized finalized diagnosis document that is the cdd basically
as i said there might be there may be there will be a paragraph relating to the uh relating to the
recoveries although all this information shall be correspondent to what you will find in the cdd
because in the cdd there will be a dtc table where the recoveries will be listed
and obviously the vehicle function shall match with the cdd that is the master document of the diagnosis
okay at the end of this paragraph of this chapter there's a um there's a there's this table that
is quite important this table and this list
in this list you can find the configuration parameters the configuration parameters is the list
of all the parameters that are uh that are presented that are mentioned in the text above
it could be for example a speed threshold or a temperature show a temperature threshold timers
uh the bouncing times uh timeouts for uh for for detecting the uh for detecting a dtc and so on
all these uh all these parameters will be listed at the end of this part of the vehicle function
since these parameters have a numerical value that you may be aware you should be aware of when you
both do uh when you bought into development or validation because uh this is very relevant
because this parameter with these parameters although uh calibrateable uh you should know the value of
this parameter because when you go to when you validate the functionality you shall know whether
a speed uh whether if a spin threshold is five kilometers per hour or 50 kilometers per hour
because it changes how the test is carried out
the values of these uh the values of these calibrations are available at least the initial
values are available here after the tables the table that lists all the parameters with the
with the respective description there's this list that uh that gives at least the first trial value for
these values although these values since are calibrateable uh the final value of this of these of these
parameters could be different from the one that you find here because these ones are calibrations
so here you will find the just initial trial the first trial value this could or could not be uh the
the value of these parameters in the final implementation could or could not be equal to the one that you
find here in this table okay this is uh uh this is a we went through all the document i think that i didn't forget
anything but anyway i think that there's another presentation i want to see if i can find something
useful in there but meanwhile um i'll take a 10 15 minutes break
so that we can uh go and take a coffee and uh i can take a look so that we can go to the other
presentation to see if there is something else that that is worth mentioning meanwhile do you have any
questions now regarding what we've discussed so far no i don't have any questions questions anybody
no everything clear no for me okay yes it's clear okay guys so let's take a 15 minutes break and see you
at uh 11 40 okay okay okay nothing actually not not for me okay not for me okay so
we're pretty much finished there is something a couple of things that uh things that i want to mention
that uh that could be contained in a uh in a vehicle function document
uh the first thing regards the uh the the functionality description the algorithm description
the part that you found uh that you that you found in the previous document written as pseudo code
uh this part uh this part uh this part here if condition then uh this shall happen another form that
could be used to um to uh to describe uh to describe the algorithm could be um instead of pseudo code
could be a uh fincit machine that is the uh that is something like uh that is something that looks
that looks like this so there is different states there is different states and the transition between one
state to another state is regulated by the uh is regulated by uh by uh by uh by condition or a set of
conditions so the transition from state one to state two is uh is uh um
uh submitted to the uh to the to the conditions that you find on the arrow this is another formalism
that is used that is used to describe the uh that is used to describe the algorithm when the specific
algorithm is uh can be synthesized as as a state machine
okay this is another thing another thing that i wanted to mention that is present in the presentation
but uh but we didn't find it in the document that i used as an example is the uh is everything that
relates to the uh to the proxy there could be some part of a given functionality uh that could be
that could be enabled by a value of a specific proxy parameter
for example a specific functionality could be um could be uh could be applicable for an architecture
that has for example a minor transmission and an automatic transmission but the functionality could
have an additional content that is enabled when you have an automated transmission and not a manual
transmission this is just an example uh in the algorithm in the in the core in the central part of
the vehicle function in the main part uh you may find the paragraph like this that uh that states
whether whether there are parts of the uh of the functionality some contents that are enabled by a
value of a specific proxy parameter do any of you know what the proxy is
all of you or none of you
i have so some idea about the proxy proxy proxy
can you say it again i cannot tell you very well
sensor
as far as i know yes
basically the pro basically proxy is something that uh is a
uh is basically something that is a set of parameters that is contained uh that is contained in issue that describes the um
that describes the uh for example the trim level for example uh something that you may find in a proxy is
uh uh uh is a type of transmission type of transmission manual automatic
when these uh when the transmission is manual the proxy has to be set
in the end of line phase has to be set to a given value whereas if the transmission is automatic
shall be set to another value or climate
manual climate or automatic climate shall be set to one value or to the other value
some function some some parts of a given functionality may be submitted to the uh to
to proxy parameters so as i said the there could be some slight differences some contents that are enabled
by uh by specific proxy values that are set in the end of line phase and in the document you may you
will find a table like this that says whether there is a um there is a there is some there is some
functionality for example selection money t no suspension suspension button uh pressure that is uh
that is enabled by the uh that is enabled by the proxy
another thing that you may find that you may find in the central part at the end of the central part of
the vf is whether this functionality um can wake up the uh can wake up the network or not
you can wake up the can network or not
and uh that's pretty much everything so some additional documents that you may find uh that you
may use uh in uh in addition to the to the vf some documents that are that are that are useful
to uh better understand the vf vehicle functionality is the dbc that describes all the signals on the on
all the networks all the signals uh that that you find in our own in every network in the vehicle
and the the cdd that contains all the diagnostic uh all the diagnostic stuff
and of course if if in case the uh some uh some link network is involved in the functionality also the
ldf file the link description file
that is the equivalent of the dbc but for link network we can see it like a like a database like
a dbc but but it's targeting to a totally network although as you may already know lin and ken are
somewhat different
okay okay
okay guys that's pretty much everything the uh
i finished we didn't take all the two hours like uh
uh but uh but there's not much stuff to uh to talk about regarding the uh regarding the vf document
so uh if you don't have any questions we can uh
uh uh we can close it here and uh in case you have uh you have any questions uh upload these files
on the kinetone academy this lesson because we don't have it there uh really actually you should
have it available i'm pretty sure you have it because i took it from there i just unloaded it from
there yeah it's there i also saw that yeah if you want i can give it a link
it is not the same uh i just drop a presentation just i just i literally downloaded it from from uh
from the uh from the uh from the space you have access to so i just send the link in the chat have
a look once i'll record okay
thank you
okay so guys that's basically it in case you have any questions regarding the uh regarding vehicle
functionalities you can uh you can uh you can either email me or uh or uh wrap me in the uh in the
in google chat and everybody as soon as possible okay
okay okay so guys thank you very much thank you for your time and uh have a nice day
bye bye bye bye bye bye